const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"The superior vena cava is derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Right anterior cardinal vein and right common cardinal vein","bool":true},{"option":"Right posterior cardinal vein and right common cardinal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Right anterior cardinal vein only","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cardinal vein only","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior cardinal vein and left common cardinal vein","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"The T wave in an electrocardiogram represents which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Atrial depolarization","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular repolarization","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular depolarization","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Fish-mouth or buttonhole stenosis is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Coarctation of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic heart disease","bool":true},{"option":"Mitral valve prolapse","bool":false},{"option":"Tetralogy of Fallot","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following statements is true about Prinzmetal variant angina?","answers":[{"option":"It is one of the common forms of episodic myocardial ischemia","bool":false},{"option":"It is caused by disruption of atherosclerotic plaque","bool":false},{"option":"It is usually relieved by rest","bool":false},{"option":"Its anginal attacks are related to physical activity","bool":false},{"option":"It is caused by coronary artery spasm","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"During a class discussion, the teacher asked about the tributaries opening in the right atrium. Which of the following does not open in the right atrium?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary vein","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is not included in the primary prevention of hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Medication","bool":true},{"option":"Dietary sodium reduction","bool":false},{"option":"Increased physical activity","bool":false},{"option":"Weight reduction","bool":false},{"option":"Avoidance of smoking","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which free radical generated in red blood cells by autooxidation converts hemoglobin to methemoglobin?","answers":[{"option":"Singlet oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Peroxy nitrite","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxyl radical","bool":false},{"option":"Superoxide","bool":true}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following antioxidants is a metalloenzyme that has three forms and is considered to be the first line of defense for protection from the injurious effects of superoxide?","answers":[{"option":"Superoxide dismutase","bool":true},{"option":"Glutathione peroxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Glutathione reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha tocopherol","bool":false},{"option":"Catalase","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Insulin enhances the uptake of triacylglycerols in adipose tissues. Which of the following enzymes is activated by insulin to facilitate this uptake?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatic lipase","bool":false},{"option":"Hormone sensitive lipase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl coenzyme-A","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoprotein lipase","bool":true},{"option":"Lecithin cholesterol acetyl transferase","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Familial hypercholesterolemia is a genetic disorder of lipid metabolism. The defect is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced transport of cholesterol from extra hepatic tissues to the liver","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired HDL metabolism due to the deficiency of Apo-A","bool":false},{"option":"Defective cholesterol degradation pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired uptake of cholesterol by tissues","bool":true},{"option":"Autosomal recessive mutation","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following is the principal apoprotein associated with low density lipoproteins?","answers":[{"option":"Apolipoprotein A","bool":false},{"option":"Apolipoprotein B-48","bool":false},{"option":"Apolipoprotein B-100","bool":true},{"option":"Apolipoprotein C-II","bool":false},{"option":"Apolipoprotein E","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of these is closely related to the partially hydrogenated oils?","answers":[{"option":"Saturated fats","bool":false},{"option":"Poly unsaturated fats","bool":false},{"option":"Cis form of fat","bool":false},{"option":"Trans form of fat","bool":true},{"option":"Mono unsaturated fats","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"The antiarrhythmic drug milrinone is preferred due to which of the following reasons?","answers":[{"option":"It directly stimulates myocardial contractility","bool":true},{"option":"It gives long-term ionotropic support in the case of heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"It prevents thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"It has a long life","bool":false},{"option":"It selectively inhibits cAMP and phosphodiesterase type IV enzymes","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"In human heart tissue, nearly 30-40% of glycerophospholipids are plasmalogens. Plasmalogens can protect mammalian tissue against damaging effects of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Biproducts of intracellular metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Ultraviolet rays","bool":false},{"option":"Chemicals","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive oxygen species","bool":true},{"option":"Medical therapy","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following drugs belongs to the class 1C antiarrhythmic?","answers":[{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Tocainide","bool":false},{"option":"Phenytoin","bool":false},{"option":"Flecainide","bool":true},{"option":"Mexilitine","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is true regarding nitrates?","answers":[{"option":"Nitroglycerine is placed under tongue because if swallowed it would be destroyed by the gastric juice","bool":false},{"option":"They are more effective as prophylactic measures taken daily than to relieve an anginal attack","bool":false},{"option":"They usually decrease venous return","bool":true},{"option":"They are selective coronary dilators","bool":false},{"option":"They constrict meningeal blood vessels causing headache","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of these represents the adverse effect of angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors due to increased levels of bradykinin in a pulmonary tree?","answers":[{"option":"Dry cough","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Skin rash and bronchodilation","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive sputum production","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the location of a sinoatrial node?","answers":[{"option":"Near the coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterolaterally at the junction of inferior vena cava and right atrium","bool":false},{"option":"Postero-inferior region of the inter atrial septum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior end of the sulcus terminalis","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial to the epicardium at the junction of superior and inferior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Proper maturation of pre-T cells involves interaction with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Reticular cells and fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial reticular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Circulating antigen","bool":true},{"option":"Hassall's corpuscles","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"The right coronary artery arises from which of the following sinuses?","answers":[{"option":"From anterior and posterior aortic sinuses","bool":false},{"option":"Right posterior aortic sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Left posterior aortic sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior aortic sinus","bool":true},{"option":"From left pulmonary vein","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following separates the atria from the ventricles?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior interventricular groove","bool":false},{"option":"Interatrial groove","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior interventricular groove","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sulcus","bool":true},{"option":"Interventricular sulcus","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following structures present in the superior mediastinum is not enclosed by the pericardium?","answers":[{"option":"Upper half of superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Initial part of inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Descending aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending aorta","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following is not present at intercalated discs?","answers":[{"option":"Dense bodies","bool":true},{"option":"Communicating junctions","bool":false},{"option":"Fascia adherentes","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junctions","bool":false},{"option":"Desmosomes","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is true about the position of a nucleus in a cardiac muscle cell?","answers":[{"option":"Single peripherally located nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple nuclei aggregated in the center","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple peripherally located nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"It is anuclear","bool":false},{"option":"Single centrally located nucleus","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the blood supply of the atrioventricular node?","answers":[{"option":"From right coronary artery in 80% of the population","bool":true},{"option":"From right coronary artery in 50% of the population","bool":false},{"option":"From left coronary artery in 80% of the population","bool":false},{"option":"From right coronary artery in 20% of the population","bool":false},{"option":"From left coronary artery in 60% of the population","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"For maintaining fetal circulation, which of the following vessels are connected via ductus venosus?","answers":[{"option":"Umbilical vein and inferior vena cava","bool":true},{"option":"Umbilical vein and cardinal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Umbilical vein and hepatic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Umbilical vein and vitelline vein","bool":false},{"option":"Umbilical vein and epigastric vein","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"The umbilical vein develops into which of the following structures in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Hemiazygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial umbilical ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Ligamentum arteriosum","bool":false},{"option":"Round ligament of the liver","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of these features is not a part of the tetralogy of Fallot?","answers":[{"option":"Interventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary infundibular stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta arising from both ventricular cavities","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophy of the right ventricular wall","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Transposition of the great vessels was observed in a male infant with obvious cyanosis and mild tachycardia. Which of these can give rise to this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Faulty spiraling of conus cordis and truncus arteriosus","bool":true},{"option":"Involution of ductus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of the endocardial cushions to fuse","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal resorption of septum primum","bool":false},{"option":"Abnormal transformation of the sixth aortic arch","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Tom was stabbed with a sword. The sword pierced the right side of his chest and went straight through his heart. Which of the following was the first structure pierced by the sword?","answers":[{"option":"Epicardium","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal serous pericardium","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous pericardium","bool":true},{"option":"Myocardium","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral serous pericardium","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following decreases in case of increased ejection fraction?","answers":[{"option":"Stroke volume","bool":false},{"option":"End diastolic volume","bool":false},{"option":"End systolic volume","bool":true},{"option":"Heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac output","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following is responsible for phase-III of the cardiac muscle action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium efflux","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium efflux","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium influx","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium influx","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"In which of the following conditions does the total peripheral resistance increase?","answers":[{"option":"Sympathetic stimulation","bool":true},{"option":"Beriberi disease","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Arteriovenous fistula","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following represents a property possessed by cardiac muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Short refractory period","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic innervation","bool":false},{"option":"Tetanization","bool":false},{"option":"Fatigue","bool":false},{"option":"Syncytium","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following is responsible for phase-II of the cardiac muscle action potential?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium efflux","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium influx","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium efflux","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium efflux","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium influx","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the cardiac cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Isovolumic contraction is a phase of fall in ventricular pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Duration is decreased as heart rate is decreased","bool":false},{"option":"Diastasis is during atrial filling","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial systole is preceeded by atrioventrical closure","bool":false},{"option":"Duration is 0.8 seconds normally","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following is a cause of hypoeffective heart?","answers":[{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":true},{"option":"Sympathetic stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenergic stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Vagal inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic inhibition","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following statements is correct about a normal electrocardiogram (ECG)?","answers":[{"option":"P-R interval is 0.4 seconds","bool":false},{"option":"Interval between QRS complex is greater than 1 second","bool":false},{"option":"QRS complex is ventricular repolarization","bool":false},{"option":"T wave is a ventricular depolarization","bool":false},{"option":"P wave is atrial depolarization","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following substances is a vasoconstrictor?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrogen ion","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":true},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium ion","bool":false},{"option":"Bradykinins","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following conditions will not increase the heart rate?","answers":[{"option":"Exercise","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Cholinergic stimulation","bool":true},{"option":"Sympathetic stimulation","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic blockage","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following events is related to the production of the first heart sound?","answers":[{"option":"End of the diastolic phase of the cardiac cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Beginning of the diastolic phase of the cardiac cycle","bool":false},{"option":"End of the systolic phase of the cardiac cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Middle 1/3rd of the diastolic phase of the cardiac cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Beginning of the systolic phase of the cardiac cycle","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following represents the value of the end-diastolic volume?","answers":[{"option":"50-70 ml","bool":false},{"option":"120-150 ml","bool":true},{"option":"150-170 ml","bool":false},{"option":"30-50 ml","bool":false},{"option":"10-30 ml","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which one of the following is a cause of sudden cardiac death?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular arrhythmia","bool":true},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Sinoatrial rhythm","bool":false},{"option":"Bundle branch block","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial tachycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is not a tributary of the right atrium?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cardinal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding cor pulmonale?","answers":[{"option":"It is characterized by left ventricular hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Most commonly caused by disorders affecting chest movements","bool":false},{"option":"It may be caused by disorders inducing pulmonary arterial vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Shows marked dilation of right ventricle without hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"It can occur following a massive pulmonary embolism","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following conditions is associated with onion skin lesions in the vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperplastic arteriosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hyaline arteriosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Atherosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Monckeberg medial sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Kawasaki disease","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is the most common valvular abnormaility?","answers":[{"option":"Myxomatous degeneration","bool":false},{"option":"Calcific aortic stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Subacute bacterial endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic heart disease","bool":false},{"option":"Dilation of ascending aorta","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Shunt between the right and left anterior cardinal vein forms which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Renal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Left brachiocephalic vein","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2016","question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Mevalonate carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Squalene synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Prenyl transferase","bool":false}]}]
export default arr